A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller, Sr. papers FA002
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Spelman Family material, 1613; S
  - Spelman, Lucy H. (Mrs. Harvey B. Spelman)
    - Real Estate (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Letter from J.G.W. Cowles to JDR re: bond against Little and Keyes estate, 1884
      - Letters from F.F. Leathers and Morris Allyn re: Iowa lands, 1884-1885
      - Correspondence with J.G.W. Cowles re: Iowa lands, 1884, 1894
      - Correspondence with Allyn Brothers re: land sale, 1887
      - Correspondence with Allyn Brothers and F.M. Brown re: land purchase, 1887
      - Tax receipt for land in Iowa, 1887
      - Correspondence re: sale of land in Iowa
      - Letter from G.W. Murray to J.D. Rogers re: deed for Iowa land to S. Carl
      - Letters from J.G.W. Cowles re: deeds for Iowa land, 1894
      - Correspondence with Allyn Brothers re: sale of Iowa land, 1894
      - Notes, memos and charts of Iowa land of HBS, 1882
    - Real Estate Taxes (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Tax notices and notes, 1881, 1885
      - Tax receipts, 1879-1890
      - Tax receipts, 1879-1891
      - Tax receipts, 1879-1882
      - Papers containing various letters and memos, re: taxes, 1887
      - Letters of F.M. Brown, 1886
      - Correspondence with G.S. Allyn and J.G.W. Cowles re: taxes and land sales, 1887
      - Correspondence with Allyn brothers re: taxes, 1887
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Pledges and receipts, Plymouth Church, Cleveland, Ohio, 1886-1888
      - Memos of Standard Oil sotck held by LHS, 1887
      - Affidavit of LHS re: water bill, 1889
      - Statement of Accounts
    - Estate (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Last Will and Testament
      - Memorial, 1897
  - Spelman, Lucy M. (Box 2)
    - Account and will preparation, 1904-1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bible study notes (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Notebooks from Austria, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1858-1859 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Includes letters to Mrs. Hawley, former teacher of LMS and LSR, 1858-1859.
    - Pledges and receipts, Plymouth Church, Cleveland, Ohio, 1886-1888
      See Box 1, Folder 10.
    - Memos concerning Standard Oil stock held by LMS
    - Statement of Accounts
      See Flat Box.
    - Death Notices (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Acknowledgements by JDR Jr. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Funeral expenses (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Last Will and Testament (Box 2, Folder 16-20)
    - Estate, 1920-1942 (Box 2, Folder 16-20)
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller papers, SL
    - Accounts, 1904-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Address Book, 1900, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Bible Study Notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Charitable Contributions, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1856-1915 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - Diaries, 1905-1914 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Education: Central High School; Oread Institute, 1855, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - French Exercise Book, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Death
      - Last Days, JDR Return, Arrangements (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Condolences
        - Condolences (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Relatives and Close Associates: Acknowledged by Written Reply (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Acknowledged by JDR Jr. Personally (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - Acknowledged by Written Reply, A-Z (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
        - Acknowledged by Engraved Card (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Acknowledgements, 1-1215 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
        - Acknowledgement Index, JDR Received (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - Acknowledgement Index, Lucy Spelman List (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Acknowledgement Index, Cards (Box 3, Folder 24)
        - Acknowledgement Index (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
        - Acknowledgement Index (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Flowers: Acknowledged by JDR Jr. Personally (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Obituaries, Tributes and Memorials (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Estate
      - Estate (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Accounting Matters (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Cleveland Teachers' Pension Fund (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Conklin, W.R., attorney. (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Jewelry Distribution (Box 4, Folder 34)
      - Legal Notes (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Property Distribution (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Schedules (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Sked, C.P., Trust (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Transfer Tax, 1915-1924 (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
      - Transfer Tax (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
      - V-W (Box 5, Folder 44)
        Vellore Medical College; Women's American Baptist Home Mission Society; Women's American Baptist Foreign Mission Society.
      - Appraisal (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Court Documents (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Last Will and Testament (Box 6, Folder 48)
      - Legal Papers (Box 6, Folder 49-51)
      - Power of Attorney (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - Transfer Tax (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Miscellany, 1920-1940 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      Correspondence about LSR, 1920-1940; "Puzzle" by the Bishop of Oxford; "Charlie Coulson" by Dr. M.L.R.
    - Miscellaneous wrapped material (Box 6)
      Miscellaneous holdings and artifacts may be closed to scholarly research due to the brittle condition of the original archival material and preservation concerns.
      - Leather wallet that contained Simon Rockefeller's notes (Box 6)
      - Leather briefcase (Box 6)
      - Artifacts from Avery Homestead (Box 6)
      - Artifact from Spelman wall (Box 6)
      - "William Philip Notes and Accounts" (Box 6)
- Miscellany, Z
  This series consists of a variety of printed matter including personal calling cards, holiday greeting cards, cards imprinted with inspirational words, and a card to acknowledge appeals to Mr. Rockefeller for charitable contributions. A bound version of the "Last Will and Testament of John D. Rockefeller" is also included in this series.
  The material in this series is not dated.
  - Birthday Acknowledgement (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Card with envelope. "Mr. Rockefeller deeply appreciates your kind remembrance of him on his birthday and sends you his cordial greetings and best wishes."
  - Calling Cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Four West Fifty-fourth Street" Contained in 2 original stationery boxes, tied with white ribbon, interleaved with tissue paper; 1 box contains envelopes.
  - Checks (Box 1, Folder 3)
    The Fifth Avenue Bank, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. National City Bank of New York, John D. Rockefeller
  - Declination of Requests (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Funeral - Dr. Fosdick's Prayer at the Funeral Service of John Davison Rockefeller (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Pocantico Hills, New York, May 26, 1937
  - Funeral - A Resolution on the Death of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    City of East Cleveland, Ohio, May 24, 1937. Embossed with City of East Cleveland seal.
  - Holiday Greeting Cards - "In the Gardens at Kijkuit" (Box 1, Folder 7)
    "Bless you for your Holiday Greetings. May the New Year be a very happy one for you."
  - Holiday Greeting Cards - "Kijkuit" (Box 2, Folder 8)
    "With hearty Christmas Greetings and all good wishes for the New Year."
  - Holiday Greeting Cards (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "With kindest thoughts and best wishes for Christmas and the New Year" Plain-edged and gold-embossed.
  - Holiday Greeting Cards (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "Bless you for your Holiday Greeting. May the New Year be a very happy one for you."
  - Inspirational Cards (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "The Best Memory System" "But as we meet and touch each day..." "I Do It Unto Thee" "It was early taught to work as well as play..." "Somebody did a golden deed..."
  - Last Will and Testament of John D. Rockefeller, June 2, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    4 copies, paperback, stitched.
  - Stationery and Envelopes - Ormond Beach, Florida (Box 3, Folder 13-13a)
    Letter-sized writing paper, printed "John D. Rockefeller, Ormond Beach, Florida" Envelopes with return address "Ormond Beach, Florida"